Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/khue-nguyen-745061263 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Triton Data Analysis

Back-End Web Development

Khue Nguyen

Al software Engineer at Katalon

Ho Chi Minh City, Vietnam

Summary

Software engineer with 5+ years of experience in back-end software development, including 3+ years of experience building and deploying deep learning models in production environments. Proficient in Python, Java with experience in database management and web development.

Experience

Katalon Al Software Engineer September 2024 - Present (7 months) Vietnam

Viettel Solutions Corporation

Al Engineer

December 2021 - September 2024 (2 years 10 months)

- Architected and implemented TesselAI, an AI platform that empowers users to label data, train, and deploy
- machine learning models, bringing \$100,000 in revenue for the first release.
- Designed and implemented multi-tenant architecture for the system, utilizing techniques such as database
- separation to enhance system scalability, security, and resource utilization.
- Developed a robust training model flow utilizing Celery and RabbitMQ to ensure efficient and reliable model training processes.
- Reduced dataset API latency by 41% (from 850ms to 500ms per request), improving application responsiveness.
- Assisted in building Human-in-the-Loop workflow that streamlines data collection from production for model retraining
- Implemented a robust monitoring and alerting system (Prometheus, Loki & Grafana) that reduced undetected issues by 25%

- Designed and implemented deployment strategies for TesselAI on Kubernetes, ensuring high availability and scalability.
- Developed Customer Relationship Management (CRM) system to streamline interaction management, data analysis, and customer relationship insights

Egitech

Game Developer

May 2021 - December 2021 (8 months)

A few projects I worked as a game developer

Project: The Noxal Game:

- A turn-based 3D tactical NFT game that allows users to purchase characters and items through their own NFT wallets.

Responsibilities:

- + Worked on the development of a mobile game using Unity game engine.
- + Collaborated with designers, artists, and QA testers to implement game mechanics, UI elements, and gameplay features.
- + Designed and implemented new features and functionalities based on client requirements and feedback.

Project: The Cricket World:

- A turn-based 2D strategy game

Responsibilities

- + Worked on the development of a mobile game using Unity game engine.
- + Implemented game mechanics, UI elements, and player controls based on client requirements.

Southern Petroleum Corporation

Software Engineer

June 2019 - May 2021 (2 years)

The first company I worked for as a software engineer, The main projects I've worked on

Project: Southern Petroleum system

- An internal system that manages all company operations, including business, human resources management, accounting subsystem, and marketing activities.

Responsibilities:

• Implemented Dockerized development environment, reducing new developer setup time by 70%.

- Participated in the development of company website features enhancing user experience.
- Designed and implemented a comprehensive gas cylinder management solution to streamline tracking, optimize inventory, and ensure gas cylinder traceability throughout their life cycle.
- Developed a next-order prediction model utilizing historical customer data to optimize gas delivery and enhance customer care.
- Developed and maintained a gas weighing software system that increased weighing accuracy and reduced processing time by 40%

Education

University of Information Technology
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (September 2016 - September 2021)